Guide to the Leland Stanford Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Leland Stanford papers
1841-1897
SC0033A
Stanford, Leland, 1824-1893.
5 Linear feet
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Gifts of Jane Lathrop Stanford, Thomas Welton Stanford, David Starr Jordan, Helen Stanford Canfield, David H. Canfield, and others; also includes purchases.
Information about Access
The materials are open for research.
BIOGRAPHY
Leland Stanford was born March 9, 1824 in Watervliet Township, New York. He was admitted to the practice of law in 1848 and married Jane Lathrop in 1850. In 1852, Stanford moved to California where he first worked as a storekeeper in Mother Lode mining camps and later became a successful Sacramento businessman. Stanford was a leader in organizing the Republican party in California and was elected governor in 1861 at the age of 37. Early in the 1860s, Stanford joined with three other Sacramento merchants--Charles Crocker, Mark Hopkins, and Collis P. Huntington--in the building of the Central Pacific Railroad. In 1885, Leland and Jane founded Leland Stanford Jr. University in memory of their son. Stanford died June 21, 1893 during his second term as United States Senator.
SCOPE AND CONTENT
Correspondence, telegrams; business, legal, financial, and official papers; speeches, journals, and newsclippings; and other materials relating to the construction of the Central Pacific Railroad, Stanford's political career, business and financial interests, and the founding and construction of Stanford University.
Access Terms
Central Pacific Railroad Company; Cesnola, Luigi Parma di, 1832-1904.; Coolidge, Charles Allerton, 1858-1936.; Goodrich Quarries..; Gordan, George.; Harrison, Benjamin, 1833-1901; Hopkins, Mark.; Huntington, Collis Potter, 1821-1900.; Jordan, David Starr, 1851-1931; Muybridge, Eadweard, 1830-1904; Nash, Herbert C.; Olmsted, Frederick Law, 1822-1903; Sawyer, Lorenzo.; Shepley, Rutan and Coolidge.; Sloss, Leon.; Southern Pacific Company; Stanford, Josiah Winslow, 1864-1937.; Stanford, Leland, 1824-1893.; Vrooman, Henry.; Walker, Francis Amasa,, 1840-1897.; Warm Springs Ranch (Calif.).; White, Andrew Dickson,, 1832-1918.; Capitalists and financiers.; Railroads--Management.; Universities and colleges--Administration.; Universities and colleges--Finance.; Vina Ranch (Calif.)
Collection Contents
- Biographical, Series 1
  - Certificate to practice law in Wisconsin, 1850 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Catalogue of Leland Stanford's Collection of Pictures, 1882 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Estate papers, 1897-1899 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Will, codicils, decree of settlement of final account and final distribution of the estate of Senator Leland Stanford.
    - In the Matter of the Estate of Leland Stanford, Appropriation and distribution... of said estate, 1897
    - In the Matter of the Estate of Leland Stanford, Decree of Settlement..., [1899]
    - Partial xerox of first item
  - Brochure on sale of ranch property from estate of Leland Stanford, 1896 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Correspondence, Series 2
  - Outgoing
    - 1840-1849 (Box 1, Folder 5)
      - to father: arrival at Clinton, 1841 May 21
      - to father: arrival at Clinton; cost of studies and courses, 1843 Jan 7
      - to Charles: his election as president of the Philotenian Society, 1843 Jan 29
      - to Charles: leaves for Cazenovia, 1844 Jan 25
      - to Asa Philip: railroad settlement, Cazenovia girls, marriage, death, morality, 1844 Feb 13
      - to Dewitt: school expenditures, 1844 Feb 29
      - to father: studies, end of term, birthday, 1844 March 10
      - to Charles: proposed profession of lawyer, idleness, ambition, 1844 March 23
      - to Philip: sale of the farm, the election, his studies, 1844 April 13
      - to Charles: girls and summer clothes, 1844 April 30
      - to Dewitt: summer clothing, 1844 May 18
      - to father: received money, invitation to speak in public, 1844 May 31
      - to Philip: tavernkeeping, horseracing, political meeting where Cassius M. Clay spoke on slavery, 1844 Oct 11
      - to Charles: flirtation, Charles's sale of his interest in Bulls Head tavern, 1844 Dec 1
      - to Dewitt: girls, studies, religion, Bulls Head lease, 1845 Jan 25
      - to Dewitt: received money, 1845 March 12
    - 1850-1859 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - to brother: advice on school and deportment to younger brother, 1850 Jan 5
      - to Hannah Clark: news of Port Washington, 1850 June 20
      - to T. W. Stanford: brotherly advice on studying, 1851 Dec 20
      - to parents: fire at Port Washington and loss of library, real estate, plans to go to California, 1852 April 1
      - to parents: sea voyage and weather, 1855 Nov 1
      - to parents: business and living conditions in Sacramento, 1856 May 4
      - to parents: counsels against sale of parents' farm, 1856 Oct 10
      - to brother: advice on studying [ts copy], 1857 Dec 20
      - to parents: California state fair, oversize fruit, election, 1859 Sep 19
      - to parents: sends $1,000, 1859 Nov 19
    - 1860-1863 (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - to parents: business and financial affairs, elections, gold and silver discoveries, 1860 May 4
      - to parents: $1,000 enclosed, desires them to move to California, 1860 Aug 10
      - gives brother Josiah power of attorney to manage and control his property, 1861 Jan 18
      - to mother: death of his father, 1862 May 23
      - to Don Ramon Castilla: letter of introduction for Josiah Stanford, 1862 May 6
      - to W. Rogers: state politics and the Union cause, 1862 Aug 8
      - to mother: building of the railroad, wishes to bring her to California, 1862 Dec 13
      - to A. A. Sargent: considers withdrawing as gubernatorial candidate, 1863 June 2
      - to Merchants Ins. Co.: request to borrow money for C.P.R.R., 1863 Aug 1
    - 1865-1869 (Box 1, Folder 8)
      - to mother: appreciation of her, desire to visit, news of family in California, 1865 Dec 24
      - to E. B. Crocker: will complete W. P. deal in any event, 1867 April 22
      - to Jane Stanford: gives her stock in Contract & Finance Co., 1868 May 30
      - to H. G. Blaisdell: suggests Charles J. Forbes as commissioner of deeds for Nevada, 1868 May 30
      - to C. Crocker: U. P. will try to get our man (telegram), 1868 Nov 13
      - to C. Crocker: did not buy that stock (telegram), 1868 Nov 21
      - to E. B. Crocker: securing right of way; wants Charley to hasten track laying, 1868 Dec 8
      - to C. Crocker: contractors and supplies (telegram), 1868 Dec 13
      - to CPRR office: send horses to meet Huntington (telegram), 1868 Dec 22
      - to CPRR office: Huntington's leaving Salt Lake by stage (telegram), 1868 Dec 27
      - to E. B. Crocker: we must name directors of SPRR, 1869 Jan 3
      - to C. Crocker: wants railroad law introduced in Utah (telegram), 1869 Jan 15
      - to C. Crocker: does not have cipher book (telegram), 1869 Jan 21
      - to CPRR office: last spike driven, 1869 May 10
    - Lincoln, Abraham (copies), 1861-1863 (Box 1, Folder 9)
      - endorsement of Dr. William Rabi by Stanford and Ira P. Rankin, 1861 April 5:
      - Stanford's list of candidates for federal appointments, 1861 [?] April:
      - letter of introduction for Huntington, 1861 Nov 29
      - would like to be consulted over appointment of Circuit Judge for California, 1862 Feb 25
      - letter of introduction for S. B. Bell, 1862 June 25:
      - railroad business, 1862 Oct 1
      - appointment of district judge for territory of Nevada, 1862 Sep 10
    - Hopkins, Mark, 1867 Feb-Apr (Box 1, Folder 10)
      - would extend raod to Goat Island; wants iron hauled from Cisco, 1867 Feb 5
      - has bought engine for drilling machine in Summit Tunnel, 1867 April 1:
      - has letter of endorsement from Latham; Latham wants to go to Donner Lake, 1867 April 5:
      - wants to know amount of judgment against C.L. Wilson; Wilson trying to combine with Oregon road, 1867 April 6:
      - wants M.H. to come down to sign contract to purchase Western Pacific, 1867 April 8:
      - will you be down tonight? (telegram), 1867 April 9:
      - Judge goes up tonight (telegram), 1867 April 9:
      - sends check for $125,000; borrowned $60,00 from Davidson, 1867 April 10:
      - urges purchase of Western Pacific, 1867 April 12:
      - as to drilling machines, Latham's trip, etc., 1867 April 16:
      - advantages of buying Western Pacific, 1867 April 19:
      - will send 26,000; McLaughlin has been in, 1867 April 29:
    - Hopkins, Mark, 1867 May-Aug (Box 1, Folder 11)
      - looking about for money; coupons payable in London, 1867 May 17:
      - about paving K Street, 1867 May 18:
      - Brumagim note - McLaughlin - Dorsey, 1867 May 28:
      - Cole adverse to Conness, People's Party, 1867 May 30:
      - ability to build W. P. without state aid, 1867 June 18:
      - as to O'Leary and the B-; did not speak at Stewart's reception, 1867 Jun 20:
      - paid notes for Sac. Valley R.R. purchase; Richardson wants to go to W. F. & Co., 1867 Aug 10
    - Hopkins, Mark, 1868 Jun-Nov (Box 1, Folder 12)
      - railroad situation in Utah, contract with Brigham Young and Mormons, 1868 June 9:
      - introducing T. G. McLaren, well- borer, 1868 Aug 6
      - contracts for grading west from Monument (telegram), 1868 Aug 28
      - Union Pacific getting Chinese laboreres, 1868 Oct 21
      - arrival at Salt Lake (telegram), 1868 Oct 31
      - wants scraper force organized and barley sent to Humboldt Wells, 1868 Nov 1
      - send message to Phelps to come to Salt Lake (with note from Crocker that it was done), 1868 Nov 3
      - re Presidential vote, 1868 Nov 3
      - on progress of U. P. line, 1868 Nov 8
      - on Stanhouse, Durant, grading, and ties, 1868 Nov 9
      - 400 teams grading west of 100 mile contract (telegram), 1868 Nov 21
      - French Loan Soc. can wait; grading contracts; line on Promontory Mts; progress of U. P., 1868 Nov 21
      - are supplies at Humboldt Wells? (telegram), 1868 Nov 29
    - Hopkins, Mark, 1868 Dec (Box 1, Folder 13)
      - progress of R. R. work in Utah, 1868 Dec 1
      - send 500 kegs (telegram), 1868 Dec 2
      - supplies for Benson, Farr & West, 1868 Dec 4
      - on situation in Utah, 1868 Dec 4
      - order for supplies to Humboldt Wells; wants Hanford or Madden as clerk (telegram, with note from Crocker to Hopkins), 1868 Dec 4
      - about beef (telegram), 1868 Dec 5
      - deliver supplies to contractors at Humboldt Wells (telegram), 1868 Dec 10
      - slow progress of our track, 1868 Dec 10
      - approved line is only proper one, 1868 Dec 13
      - expects to meet Huntington at Omaha (telegram), 1868 Dec 16
    - Hopkins, Mark, 1869 (Box 1, Folder 14)
      - will get all done here that I can but we must rely on Strobridge's forces, 1869 Jan 15
      - will start from Salt Lake tomorrow (telegram), 1869 Jan 21
      - Commissioners leaving Monday by stage, meet them at Elko, 1869 Jan 29
      - to examine line with Commissioners; I have no pleasure in the thought of Railroad, 1869 Jan 29
      - arriving at Elko Thursday; send 200 kegs to Benson Farr & West (telegram), 1869 Jan 31
      - matters satisfactory (telegram), 1869 March 10:
      - thinks Commissioners were set for U. P., 1869 March 14:
      - arrangements made for $100,000 (telegram), 1869 July 19:
      - he [C.P. Stanford?] should be declared bankrupt (telegram), 1869 July 30:
      - Vallejo R. R. trying to get mail contract, 1869 Aug 13
      - Mills & Ralston request we hold back drafts, 1869 Aug 13
    - Hopkins, Mark, 1870-1873 (Box 1, Folder 15)
      - Brannan stock, 1870 May 31:
      - glad Larkin's stock is secured, 1870 July 5:
      - telegram, 1873 March 25:
      - send $135,000 to C.P.H. (telegram), 1873 March 27:
      - financial instructions (telegram), 1873 Aug 15
      - look over bills payable and decide what is best (telegram), 1873 Sep 30
      - have done nothing in that matter (telegram), 1873 Sep 30
      - you must advise him (telegram), 1873 Oct 1
      - have advised Huntington of $120,000 (telegram), 1873 Oct 1
      - will be up tomorrow night (telegram), 1873 Oct 3
      - have deposited with Belloc Freres for Von Hoffman $130,000 (telegram), 1873 Oct 3
    - 1870-1879 (Box 1, Folder 16)
      - to CPRR: letter of introduction for Mrs. Henry Weatherbee, 1870 Dec 23
      - to CPRR: letter of introduction for Mrs. Henry Weatherbee, 1871 April 17
      - to Cmte on Nevada University: CPRR offers 20 acres and $500, 1872 Feb 21
      - to E. G. Northrup: unable to be of assistance [verifax copy], 1872 June 26
      - to W. M. Stewart: tel., must reserve house and lot for Downs, 1872 Oct 21
      - to C.P. Huntington: order for 500 S.P. bonds to Latham as collateral, 1873 Dec 26
      - to C. P. Huntington: taxes; Brannan suit (telegram), 1874 Jan 23
      - to Simon Cameron: offer of railroad courtesies [verifax copies], 1874 Oct 1
      - to C. P. Huntington: wants to control U. P., 1875 May 1
      - to Sacramento trustees: construction of boilers and pumps for city waterworks in CPRR shops, 1877 July 10
      - note to H. H. Ellis (SF police chief) re protection from Kearney mob with reply from Ellis, 1877:
      - to Gen. McComb, 1878 Feb 21
    - 1880-1885 (Box 1, Folder 17)
      partial list of contents:
      - to "Dear Sister": sends money, 1881 Feb 5
      - to Jane Stanford (telegram), 1881 [no month] 27
      - to Jane Stanford: arrived safely in New York, 1882 June 6
      - to Jane Stanford: his visit to Albany and her mother's health, 1882 June 9
      - to J.D.B. Stillman: re price of the book, 1882 July 26
      - to J. D.B.Stillman: re Muybridge suit, 1882 Oct 23
      - to J.D.B. Stillman: Muybridge was an "instrument to carry out my ideas", 1883 Jan 5
      - to "Dr.": on his health; they go to Europe soon, 1883 May 25
      - to Jane Stanford (from Bad Kissingen): on taking the waters, 1883 Aug 10
      - to Leland Jr.: (from Bad Kissingen), 1883 Aug 21
      - to Leland Jr: (from Bad Kissingen), 1883 Aug 30
      - to Leland Jr. (from Hamburg), 1883 Sep 9
      - to J.D.B.Stillman: re money and possible suit against Osgood & Co., 1883 Oct 25
      - to Jesse Grant: re feasibility of railroad from Constantinople to the Persian Gulf (photocopy), 1885 March 31
      - to Andrew White: re Holley's theory on telescopes, 1885 April 18
      - to Fred. Grant: condolences on death of U. S. Grant, 1885 July [?]
    - 1886-1889 May (Box 1, Folder 18)
      - to J. W. Knox: Electioneer to cover Knox's mare, 1886 Jan 25
      - to RR officials: extend courtesies for Miss A. Lathrop, 1886 Feb 9
      - to Ariel Lathrop (tel): send Miss. Valley Construction Co. stock, 1886 July 22
      - to Pres. Grover Cleveland: support for P. O. in San Francisco, 1887 March 3
      - to J. Stanford (tel): travel plans, 1887 May 30
      - to J. Stanford (tel): travel plans, 1887 May 31
      - to C. Huntington (tel): attitude in investigation by Pac. Ry. Commission, 1887 Sep 23
      - to T. Hopkins: location of new depot; no liquor to be sold in vicinity, 1888 Jan 8
      - to Robert Bonner: re Bonner's horse Lucy Cuyler, 1888 Dec 28
      - to W.S.U. Clement: please give Bancroft some facts on Stanford's life, 1889 Feb 15
      - to Mrs. Henry Vrooman (tel): condolences on death of Mr. Vrooman, 1889 April 11
      - to Mrs. A. Carter (tel): sending $50 contribution, 1889 May 31
    - 1889 Aug-1889 Nov (Box 1, Folder 19)
      - to J. Stanford (2 tel): travel plans, 1889 Aug 6-7
      - to J. Stanford (2 tel): Jane at Sissous, 1889 Aug 24-25
      - to J. Stanford: her health, his activities at home and in business, 1889 Aug 25
      - to J. Stanford (tel): her health, 1889 Aug 27
      - to J. Stanford: health matters, boys dormitory progressing, 1889 Aug 31
      - to J. Stanford: gave orders to start girls dormitory; thoughts on high school buildings and faculty houses, 1889 Sep 1
      - to J. Stanford (2 tel): awaiting her return, 1889 Sep 3
      - to J. Stanford (6 tel): mostly travel plans, 1889 Oct 16-28
      - to Robert Bonner: sale of horse Sunol to Bonner, 1889 Nov 2
      - to D. J. Brown: sending portrait to the Leland Stanford Div. No. 283 (locomotive engineers), 1889 Nov 11
    - 1890 (Box 1, Folder 20)
      - to R. Bonner: re horse Sunol, 1890 Feb 7
      - to A. G. Porter: re appointment [photostat copy], 1890 Feb 18
      - to W. Carr: re appintment, 1890 Feb 29
      - to [B.F.] Tracey: letter of condolence [mss. copy], 1890 March
      - to W. Blaine: letter of condolence [mss. copy], 1890 March
      - to Mrs. T. Hopkins (tel): relays Mrs. Stanford's thanks for flowers, 1890 Apr 6
      - to S. T. Gage: instructions on letters from Huntington, 1890 April 29
      - to R. Bonner: re horse Sunol, 1890 May 25
      - to R. Bonner: re horse Sunol, 1890 Dec 13
    - 1891-1892 Apr (Box 1, Folder 21)
      - to Robert Bonner: re Sunol and other horses, 1891 Dec 3
      - to Archbishop Riordan: re possible RR track through Hopkins' land [Menlo Park?] [photocopy], 1892 Feb 29
      - to Huntington, Stillman, and Hubbard: re future cooperation on new enterprises; signed by Stanford and Crocker, 1892 April 22
    - 1892 May-1893 (Box 1, Folder 22)
      - to T. W. Stanford: his health and issue of tariffs, 1892 May 30
      - to A. Lathrop: re horses, 1892 Aug 8
      - to B. Harrison (tel): condolences on wife's death, 1892 Oct 25
      - to Mrs. E. F. Beale (tel): condolences, 1893 April 22
      - to F. Shay: the Stillman matter and other business concerns, 1893 June 19
    - letters of recommendation for women for jobs with S. F. Mint, 1869-1874 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Incoming
    - Arnold, Sir Edwin, 1892- 1892 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - B, 1865-1893 (Box 1, Folder 25)
      - Bank of CA: 1/2/1869 notes to Selby & others charged to Stanford
      - Barton: 5/7/1889 on problem facing wine grape growers
      - Bellows: 1/19/1865 introduction of Johannes Schlarbaum, engineer; 4/20/1872: introduction of Miss LeClercg
      - Benchley: 5/31/1893 reference for Albert Scheer
      - Berry: 5/9/1892 LS Jr. memorial tree in Anaconda, MT
      - Bey: 3/14/1886 asking help for Turkish soldiers
      - Boruck: 2/2/1885 as to McGlashan and the senatorial contest
      - Bower: 11/29/1890 Sunol's trotting times
    - C, 1868-1891 (Box 1, Folder 26)
      - Carpenter: 4/11/1890 on Col. Markham's candidacy for governor; 10/1/1891 (tel) on opening day of university
      - Clements: 10/20/1868 (tel) grading work on RR in Utah
      - Cleveland: 1886 envelope; 1/19/1889 please see me this evening
      - Crawford: 9/25/1889 (tel) invitation from citizens of Willows, CA
      - Crocker: 11/9/1868 (tel) too late to organize scrapers west of Humboldt Wells
      - Crocker: 1/21/1869 (tel) Col. Williamson coming
    - de Wellens, E. (Baroness), 1885 (Box 1, Folder 27)
      - 1885 Feb. 23: thanks for biographical memoir of LS Jr.
      - 1885 June 2: LS Jr. appeared in a dream
    - F, 1866-1890 (Box 1, Folder 28)
      - Fenton: 1/19/1880 thank you for your hospitality
      - Ferris: 4/18/1866 enclosing trust deed of Mrs. Margaret Ferris (deed attached)
      - Flood: 10/10/1888 (tel) father still very sick
      - Foote: 4/14/1890 political praise for Stanford
      - French: 4/7/1883 with comments on HORSE IN MOTION
      - Frye: 1/17/1889 thanks for $7000 gift to Bates College (Maine)
      - Fuller: n.d. regrets on an invitation
    - Grant, Frederick D., 1885-1892 (Box 1, Folder 29)
      Partial list of contents:
      - 1885 July 20 on U.S. Grant's book and illness
      - 1889 March 20 on FG's appointment to Austrian mission
      - 1889 May 14 on trip to Vienna and reception there
      - 1891 Oct. 11 on statue of U.S. Grant in Chicago; destruction of European grape vines
      - 1892 Feb. 24 introduction of Mr. Watawabi (Japanese delegate)
    - Grant, Ulysses S., 1884 (Box 1, Folder 30)
      - 1884 June 2 requesting railroad passes
      - 1884 July 2 invitation to Grant home
      - [1884 ?] U.S. Grant to Purdy's Station Harlem RR
    - Grant family, 1890- 1893 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Gray, George E., 1868 (Box 2, Folder 1)
      - 1868 Sept. 22 (tel) about grading contracts
      - 1868 Oct. 9 progress of railroad work in Utah
      - 1868 Oct. 9 (tel) wants bill of lading
      - 1868 Oct. 11 about grading work in Utah, with copies of communications from Durant and Carter
      - 1868 Oct. 15 about grading work in Utah; following 2 letters were enclosed:
      - 1868 Oct. 12 E. F. Benson to Gray and 10/12/1868 M. Carter to Gray regarding grading contracts
      - 1868 Oct. 16 (tel) will cost more
      - 1868 Oct. 17 (tel) meeting with contractors
      - 1868 Oct. 22 (tel) asking confirmation of payment request
    - G, 1889-1893 (Box 2, Folder 2)
      - Gage: 7/2/1890 public opinion of Stanford, political news, Huntington and Crocker; 3/9/1893 [tel] birthday greetings
      - Gibbons, Cardinal: 3/2/1889 requesting assistance for Mr. James R. Randall
      - Gibbons, John: 4/13/1891 encloses letter from Fr. Casanova re statue of Fr. Junipero (attached)
      - Greenwood: n.d. poor reception for her lecture in Marysville
    - Harrison, Benjamin, 1888- 1893 (Box 2, Folder 3)
      - 1888 Nov. 22: reply to congratulatory telegram from LS
      - 1891 April 26: acceptance of invitation
      - 1892 June 14: social note
      - 1893 Feb. 25: dropping by this evening at 8:30 to complete our talk
      - 1893 March 2: on his lecturing at Stanford University
      - 1891 pamphlet, itinerary of President Harrison's tour of the Pacific Coast
      - Executive Mansion envelope address to LS in London (no letter)
    - Huntington, 1869- 1890 (Box 2, Folder 4)
      - 1868-1869 (2 tel) on travel arrangements
      - 1873 Oct. 24 (tel) CPRR finances [in code with translation]
      - 1873 Oct. 26 (tel) CPRR finances [in code with translation]
      - 1874 Jan. 22 (tel) to Mark Hopkins re value of land [in code with translation]
      - 1885 Jan. 12 (tel) are you running against Sargent
      - 1886 May 8 to S. Gage, would like to see Sargent as next CA senator
      - 1890 April 15 retracts his charge against Stanford of April 9
      - n.d. (tel) against selling of Southern Pacific bonds
    - H, 1869-1891 (Box 2, Folder 5)
      - Harrison: 2/22/1891 request for a meeting
      - Haymond: 1/23/1884 delegation from California; Colton case
      - Heald: 6/8/1889 on Stanford's proposed World Arbitration League
      - Hooker, J.D.: 6/90/1880 offer of tour of Kew Gardens
      - Hooker, J.:12/31/1872 [?92] social note
      - Hopkins: 4/9/1869 (tel) re departure of commissioners
      - Hotchkiss: 4/13/1890 expressing political support
      - Hull: 11/8/1890 re his hymn for the University (not enclosed)
    - J-K, 1884-1890 (Box 2, Folder 6)
      - Jameson: 1/1/1886 enclosing permit to ride in postal cars
      - Kearney: 5/7/1884 condolences; employment business
      - Kilburn to Haymond: 4/11/1890 support for Stanford
    - Logan family, 1884- 1890 (Box 2, Folder 7)
      - John A. Logan: 6/8/1886 on reception for GAR members in Sacramento
      - Cullom, Shelby M.: 12/28/1886 on John A. Logan's funeral
      - Mrs. John A. Logan: 3/14/1887 personal matters
      - John A. Logan,Jr: 3/15/1887 thanks for assistance and news of his marriage
      - [1887]: family ackowledgement of sympathy with name cards
      - 12/31/1886: funeral ticket and program
    - L, 1879-1890 (Box 2, Folder 8)
      - Latham, H.: 4/19/1890 appreciation for Stanford's accomplishments
      - Latham, M.S.: 8/13/1879 requests a meeting
      - Lathrop: n.d. Stillman arrived